CONTACT

+44 7812 163982

dvdjms@hotmail.com

david-james-2b949979

github.com/dvdjms

Edinburgh EH12 5DH

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages

- Python
- **JavaScript**
- Java
- C#
- HTML & CSS

Technologies

- Django
- Flask
- **Express**
- Spring
- React
- ASP.net
- **PostgreSQL**
- Styled-Components
- **Bootstrap**

Other

- Git & GitHub
- Command Line Tools
- Package Managers

PROFILE

Driven software engineer with a strong focus on frontend and backend technologies. Bringing over a decade of experience in accounts and administration, coupled with five years of teaching English as a Foreign Language. My journey into the world of technology began with Harvard's CS50, and I have since honed my skills through CodeClan's Professional Software Development course in Edinburgh.

TRAINING

CodeClan

Sep 2022 to Feb 2023

Comprehensive 16-week programming course. SQA Accredited (Level 8). With over 800 hours of practical coding, individual and groups projects, and expert-led tuition. Included OOP, TDD, UX design, agile methodologies, version control, command line, and pair-programming.

PROJECTS View Portfolio

Movie Watchlist

Python/Flask/PostgreSQL

 Flask application incorporating simple CRUD actions which allow a user to input directors and movies to keep tabs on their viewing. Users can rate the movies they've seen and visit individual director and movie pages, using RESTful APIs. Solo project.

Learn Scotland

JavaScript/React/Express/Mongodb

 Full stack React application about Scotland allowing a user to interact with quizzes, see scores on a leader board, and post comments. This included a multiple choice, drag & drop, and map location quiz. Group project.

WeatherWise

Python/Django/React/SQLite3

• Developed a fully responsive Weather app for a user to search 45,000 cities and get 24 hour and 10-day weather forecasts, taking advantage of APIs from openweathermap.org and met.no. Includes a My Locations dashboard with local time zones. Solo project.

EDUCATION

MA International Communication University of Leeds

BSc (Hons) Psychology Open University

BA (Hons) Media StudiesDe Montfort University

VOLUNTEERING

Collaborating with the Scottish Tech Army to automate website updates using Jira and Squarespace via Zapier. Focused on updating project information and pinning map locations.

ACTIVITIES

Learning new technologies.

Independent travel to Europe, Asia, and North & South America.

Hiking and adventure.

World Cinema.

EXPERIENCE

Contact Tracer - Test and Protect Scotland

Oct 2020 to Sep 2022

NHS Lothian, Edinburgh

- Conducting in-depth interviews with Covid-19 positive cases. Identifying contacts, high risk situations, public health concerns and infection patterns.
- Using CMS database to record information and communicate with Covid-19 positive cases and their contacts.
- Working with employers to identify high risk individuals offering public health advice and guidance on best practice.
- Supporting the rest of the team, sharing knowledge, experience, and best practice to support improvements to overall program.

English Teacher – Freelance Online

Aug 2019 to Aug 2021

Whales English, Beijing, China

- Educating Chinese students from ages 5-17 in classes of two.
- Using video software, with advanced teaching tools and accessories.
- Trial classes for marketing to new students and parents, with bonus incentives.
- Writing reports for parents and marking weekly homework.

English Teacher

Feb 2018 to Feb 2019

Wall Street English, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Adult learners of all levels targeting receptive and productive skills.
- Individual attention, assessment, and feedback to aid areas for improvement.
- Social Club classes with up to 26 students. Self-prepared lessons, using creativity, PowerPoint, and interactive activities.
- Demonstrated strong leadership and relationship building to facilitate an optimal learning environment.

English Language Instructor

Mar 2014 to Dec 2017

Cheonan, Jeju City, Jincheon - South Korea

- Taught all levels of English to elementary, middle school, and high school classes of up to 12 students, with experience in one-to-one learning.
- Created activities targeting receptive and productive skills.
- Taught Media Studies to advanced level students.
- Hosted events with up to 80 students for puzzles and games.

Treasury Accountant

Jul 2007 to Jan 2014

Avison Young, Birmingham

- Key performer in a highly pressurised target driven environment to reconcile high profile accounts with up to £70 million of monthly transactions.
- Proven abilities in investigating, analysing, and problem solving.
- Resolved complex and challenging problems entailing in-depth investigation.
- Interpreted and presented numerical data accurately Strong Excel.
- Made substantial contributions to improve team efficiency and effectiveness.
- Improved quality and accuracy of reconciliations with advanced Excel skills.
- Collaborated with internal and external stakeholders to deliver results.